

ABOUT ME

Dedicated and customer-focused with a successful background in leading high performing teams to meet or exceed objectives. A tactical and inspiring team builder with experience in training, team development, and delivering excellence.

Driven Developer with 6 years of experience in Full-Stack
Development. An inspiring and conscientious leader with a strong background in team development and a solid reputation for assessing business needs, developing cost-saving solutions, increasing sales, and driving customer satisfaction.

LINKS

Facebook:

https://www.facebook.com/clochenberg/

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/clochenberg/

Portfolio:

https://clochenberg.co.za

Github:

https://github.com/webonly-solutions

CHRISTO LOCHENBERG

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

- 84 Jim van der Merwe street, Centurion, 0157, South Africa
- +27 61 523 9126
- ☑ info@clochenberg.co.za

WORK EXPERIENCE

BENDEL PRINTERS

Boshoff (Free State) Feb 1993 - Jun 1994

Designer

- Prepared graphic items according to corporate brand guidelines.
- Took client measurements and adjusted patterns accordingly.
- Provided assistance with completing project designs created by the technical department.
- Collaborated closely with clients to ascertain effective marketing and designs, define scopes of projects, set budgets, and determine schedules for completion.

PSONIX COMPUTERS •

Johannesburg (Gauteng) Jul 1994 - Aug 1999

Business Owner

- Provided IT support to clients
- Installed network infrastructure
- Sourced new Business
- Selling of hardware & Software
- Maintained small businesses

PICK 'N PAY

Johannesburg (Gauteng) Aug 1999 - Feb 2001

IT Technician

- Provided customers and users of various software systems the information needed regarding maintenance requirements to qualify for OEM warranties and to follow industry best practices.
- Improved customer service by assisting in the enhancement of the company's technical support process.
- Negotiated with vendors to purchase replacement hardware and software products and sought advice to resolve more complex issues.
- Responded to customer emails to provide service within standard response time set by the company.
- Communicated with users by telephone to determine the problems they were facing,m and gave instructions for testing solutions to find the causes of the issues.
- Troubleshoot computer malfunctions by disassembling computer systems to find resolutions.

CLOUD 9 COMPUTER SYSTEMS CC

Johannesburg / Pretoria Mar 2001 - Jan 2012

Business Owner

- Improved customer service by assisting in the enhancement of the company's technical support process.
- Eliminated security breaches by updating software versions and installing new software when necessary.

- Responded to customers experiencing connectivity issues and provide step-by-step instructions to resolve issues including rebooting hardware.
- Set up new PC systems and laptops for new employees including server permissions and downloaded the software as per position requirements.
- Designed and set up new workstations for staff, including hardware, software, and required accessories.

TSEBO HOLDINGS & OPERATIONS

Port Elizabeth (Eastern Cape) Feb 2011 - May 2013

IT Manager

- Supervised schedules of projects and manage resources needed according to specifications given by stakeholders and owners.
- Paid close attention to customers' concerns and addressed their queries and achieved an exceptional level of customer service.
- Analyzed cost benefits and ROI and created strategic plans outlining the feasibility of company projects.
- Identified and solved project issues and escalated complex issues to the supervisor for remediation.
- Collaborated with project personnel to determine problems and resolve issues quickly and efficiently.
- Responsible for monitoring various company databases to ensure the accuracy of inventory.
- Supervised on-site and off-site professional teams in completing diverse IT projects.
- Purchased software, hardware, and infrastructure necessary for the company to operate efficiently.
- As needed, arranged for and/or conducted onsite training for employees.

SPECTECH SERVICES (PTY) LTD

Johannesburg / Pretoria Jul 2013 - Present

Business Owner

- Created the scope and requirements for company projects.
- Conducted negotiations to resolve disagreements and misunderstandings to successfully resolve conflicts to satisfy both parties.
- As needed, arranged for and/or conducted onsite training for employees.
- Worked tirelessly to resolve customers' problems to their satisfaction, which resulted in a loyal customer base and increased the company's positive reputation.
- Purchased software, hardware, and infrastructure necessary for the company to operate efficiently.
- Responsible for monitoring various company databases to ensure the accuracy of inventory.
- Verified supplier's adherence to contract specifications, quality of material delivered, and schedules of delivery.
- Created promotional strategies to increase business while remaining within budgetary guidelines of the company.

WEB ONLY SOLUTIONS (PTY) LTD

Pretoria Gauteng) Nov 2016 - Present

Business Owner

• Created promotional strategies to increase business while remaining within budgetary guidelines of the company.

- Enforced existing company policies and updated those that were not effective to keep the company abreast and aware of changing markets.
- Verified supplier's adherence to contract specifications, quality of material delivered, and schedules of delivery.
- Generated and administered an annual operating budget and prevented going over budget to allow the business to continue to be sustainable and profitable.

EDUCATION

HTS POTCHEFSTROOM

Potchefstroom (North West) 1991

High school diploma

Subjects:

- Afrikaans
- English
- Maths
- Science
- Electronics
- History
- Accounting

UDEMY

Pretoria (Gauteng) 2019

Python

- Integers, strings, and floats
- Attributes
- List comprehensions
- Functions + conditionals
- File Processing
- Modules
- Data Analysis
- Numpy Arrays
- Tkinter + GUI Widgets
- Database interaction

UDEMY

Pretoria (Gauteng) 2019

Progressive Web Apps (PWA)

App Manifest PWA Browser Support

- Device Emulation
- Events in PWA
- Async code in Javascript
- Firebase
- Indexed Database
- CSS & Media queries
- Animations
- Viewport + Scaling
- Web Push
- Databases

UDEMY

Pretoria (Gauteng) 2020

The Complete Web Developer in 2020 - Zero to Mastery

- Advanced HTML 5
- Advanced CSS
- CSS Grid
- Bootstrap
- Advanced Javascript
- DOM Manupilation
- NPM + NPM Scripts
- React.js + Redux
- HTTP | JASON | AJAX
- APIs
- Node.js + Express.js
- Databases
- Project Deployment

SKILLS

MULTI-TASKING ABILITIES	ANALYTICAL SKILLS
TIME MANAGEMENT	CONCEPTUAL THINKER
SELF-MOTIVATED PROFESSIONAL	HTML KNOWLEDGE
SOFTWARE TESTING	JAVASCRIPT
REACT	РНР